Guide to the album 'A Trip in Algeria' by TAYLOR, H. E. Irving AD.MC.040
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
A trip in Algeria by H. E. Irving Taylor
December 1901 – April 1902
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Taylor, H.E. Irving
Quaritch, Bernard
AD.MC.040
48 Photographic Prints Album, oblong 8vo (18.2 x 24.5 cm), pp. [2], 48; printed title 'The interchangeable photo-scrap album no trimming or mounting required' (London, M.W. & Co.), 48 black and white glossy prints (10.5 x 15.5 cm)
A visual and written record of a trip to Algeria at the opening of the 20th century (48 images) undertaken by H.E. Irving Taylor and his travelling companion, Mr Shepherd, comprising Taylor's attractive, clear photographs alongside his engaging and enthusiastic accompanying narrative. Taylor and Shepherd's trip, undertaken in January 1902, took them to Algiers, Constantine, El Kantara, Biskra, Sidi Okba, Kherrata, and the Djurdjura mountain range, the pair travelling by train, trap, bicycle, camel, and on foot. Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks.
Album, oblong 8vo (18.2 x 24.5 cm), pp. [2], 48; printed title 'The interchangeable photo-scrap album no trimming or mounting required' (London, M.W. & Co.), 48 black and white glossy prints (10.5 x 15.5 cm) captioned and dated, the first 39 surrounded with ink notes in a neat hand; light foxing to endpapers; bound in dark green cloth, 'Photographs' in gilt to upper cover, 'Algerian photographs' inked to top edge, 'Algeria 1902' to spine; extremities a little worn, spine slightly discoloured; very good; note to verso of title signed 'H. E. Irving Taylor'.
Box AD_MC_040
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access. Please contact Akkasah Center for Photography, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection acquired from Bernard Quaritch Ltd in August 2018
Arrangement
Album, oblong 8vo (18.2 x 24.5 cm), pp. [2], 48; printed title 'The interchangeable photo-scrap album no trimming or mounting required' (London, M.W. & Co.), 48 black and white glossy prints (10.5 x 15.5 cm).
Biographical
From the Venn Catalogue of Alumni Cantabrigiensis: "Taylor, Henry Edward Irving. Adm. at PEMBROKE, Oct. 1894. 3rd s. of the Rev. Charles Johnson (St John's College, Oxford, 1843), of 'The Larches,' Banstead, Surrey. B. Aug. 24, 1867, at Folkestone. Schools [Blackheath proprietary; The Leys, Cambridge, and] Hanover Square School of electrical engineering and at the City and Guilds College, 1889-92. Employed by the L.B.&.S.C. Railway and at works in Camden Town before residence. Matric. Michs. 1894; B.A. 1897; M.A. 1905. Assistant Master at Crewkerne School, Somerset, 1897-8; private tutor, 1898-1903; Head Master of a private School in Surrey, 1903-32. Of Coolinge, Reigate, Surrey, where he died June 30, 1943. Brother of Decimus A. G. (1890) and Chapman C. A. (1884). ( City and Guilds Coll. Reg.; The Times, July 2, 1943.)"
"Henry Edward Irving TAYLOR Approx. lifespan: 1867–1943 Adm Pembroke College 1894:10 3rd s. of Rev. Charles Johnson TAYLOR ( St John's College [Oxford] (1843), of 'The Larches,' Banstead, Surrey, b. Folkestone, [Kent], 1867:08:24 Schools [Blackheath proprietary [Kent], The Leys, CB, [Cambridgeshire], Hanover Sch: Square School of electrical engineering [London], Sch: City and Sch: Guilds College City and Guilds, [London], 1889-92 Employed: by the L.B.&.S.C. Railway and at works Camden Town, [London], before residence. Matric 1894:10MT: BA 1897 MA 1905 Assistant Master at:: Sch: Crewkerne School Crewkerne, Somerset, 1897-98 private Tutor: 1898-1903 Headmaster of:: private School Surrey, 1903-32 Of Coolinge, Reigate, Surrey, d. 1943:06:30 brother of Decimus A. G. TAYLOR (1890) brother of Chapman C. A. TAYLOR (1884) ( City and Guilds College Reg.; The Times 1943:07:02)"
http://venn.lib.cam.ac.uk/cgi-bin/search-2018.pl?sur=Taylor&suro=w&fir=Henry+Edward+Irving&firo=w&cit=&cito=c&c=all&z=all&tex=&sye=&eye=&col=all&maxcount=50
From the Quaritch catalogue: "Taylor appears to have been a musician – the Bodleian Library holds a number of songs and anthems composed by him, published between 1903 and 1934 – and he clearly took a great interest in Arabic music."
Content Description
A visual and written record of a trip to Algeria at the opening of the 20th century (48 gelatin silver images) undertaken by H.E. Irving Taylor and his travelling companion, Mr Shepherd, comprising Taylor's attractive, clear photographs alongside his engaging, well-written and enthusiastic accompanying narrative. Taylor and Shepherd's trip, undertaken in January 1902, took them to Algiers, Constantine, El Kantara, Biskra, Sidi Okba, Kherrata, and the Djurdjura mountain range, the pair travelling by train, trap, bicycle, camel, and on foot.
Algeria; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Quaritch, Bernard
- The front cover of the album 'A Trip in Algeria'., Circa December 1901 – April 1902; AD_MC_040_ref1; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Algeria; English Writing
- The inside front cover of the album 'A Trip in Algeria'., Circa December 1901 – April 1902; AD_MC_040_ref2; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Algeria
- A blank page in the album 'A Trip in Algeria'., Circa December 1901 – April 1902; AD_MC_040_ref3; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
- A blank page in the album 'A Trip in Algeria'., Circa December 1901 – April 1902; AD_MC_040_ref4; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
- The 'A Trip in Algeria' album's title page (The Interchangeable photo-scrap album, M. W. & Co. London)., Circa December 1901 – April 1902; AD_MC_040_ref5; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  English Writing; Algeria; Advertisements
- A page with an explanatory note signed by H. E. Irving Taylor., Circa December 1901 – April 1902; AD_MC_040_ref6; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  English Writing; Signatures; Algeria
- An arch in the Rhummel Gorge (Gorges du Rhummel), Constantine., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref7; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  English Writing; Constantine, Algeria; Landscapes; Water; Rivers; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
- A view of Constantine., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref8; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Constantine, Algeria; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Rivers; Trains; Transportation; Algiers, Algeria
- The southwestern corner of Constantine., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref9; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Rivers; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Constantine, Algeria; English Writing; Water
- Constantine and the Rhummel Gorge., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref10; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Constantine, Algeria; Food; Tea/Coffee; Rivers; Water; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- A view of the Sahara Desert taken from a train., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref11; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Constantine, Algeria; Trains; Transportation; Deserts; Algiers, Algeria; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Birds; Animals; Lakes; Water; El Kantara, Algeria
- The Oasis of El Kantara., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref12; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Oases; Bridges; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Rivers; Palm Trees; Water; El Kantara, Algeria
- A view of Dahraouïa, El Kantara with the Gorge of El Kantara in the background (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref13; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hotels; Mountains/Hills; Palm Trees; English Writing; Deserts; Tea/Coffee; Drinks/Beverages; Buildings; Biskra, Algeria; Oases; El Kantara, Algeria
- The Hotel Bertrand, El Kantara (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref14; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  English Writing; Hotels; El Kantara, Algeria; Mountains/Hills; Hunting; Oases; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
- A portrait of a Messouãn, Taylor's guide, crouching in a cemetery in El Kantara (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref15; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Men; Head Covers/Veils; Cemeteries; Individual Portraits; Mountains/Hills; Palm Trees; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; El Kantara, Algeria; Hotels; Individual Portraits
- A view of a village in El Kantara with the Aurès Mountains in the background (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref16; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; El Kantara, Algeria; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Deserts; Oases; Rivers; Bicycles/Tricycles; Donkeys; Animals
- A portrait of Messouãn, Taylor's guide, in an alley in the village of El Dahraouïra, El Kantara (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref17; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Buildings; Streets/Roads; Men; Individual Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress; Women; Girls; Children; El Kantara, Algeria
- A view of the 'left-hand rock' of the Gorge of El Kantara (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref18; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Men; Hotels; Mountains/Hills; El Kantara, Algeria
- The 'right-hand rock' of the Gorge of El Kantara, the El Kantara railway bridge is in the background (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref19; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Agriculture/Farms; Women; Mountains/Hills; Palm Trees; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; El Kantara, Algeria; Bridges; Trains; Transportation
- The oasis in El Kantara (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref20; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Rivers; Water; Mountains/Hills; Palm Trees; Music; Landscapes; Oases; El Kantara, Algeria
- A portrait of Messouãn,Taylor's guide, at the river passing through the Gorge of El Kantara (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref21; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Men; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Rivers; Oases; Mountains/Hills; Water; Palm Trees; Music; Biskra, Algeria; El Kantara, Algeria; Bridges
- A group portrait of seven boys and young men in El Kantara (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref22; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boys; Head Covers/Veils; Children; Group Portraits; Irrigation; Agriculture/Farms; Palm Trees; El Kantara, Algeria; Gardens; Rivers; Water
- A palm tree forest in the oasis at El Kantara (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref23; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Palm Trees; Forest/Woodlands; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English language; El Kantara, Algeria; Oases; Agriculture/Farms; Praying; Gardens
- The Gorge of El Kantara taken from the north side., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref24; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Railways; Trains; Transportation; Oases; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Praying; Mountains/Hills; El Kantara, Algeria; Biskra, Algeria
- People at the market in Biskra., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref25; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Markets; Crowds; Men; Biskra, Algeria; Camels; Buildings; Mosques; Food; Regional/National Dress; Religious Sites; Palm Trees; Animals; Architecture; Street Vendors; Workers; Railways; Trains; Transportation; Deserts; Oases; Mountains/Hills; Head Covers/Veils
- A portrait of Taylor's guide sitting in front of an ancient Turkish fort in Biskra (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref26; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Individual Portraits; Men; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Biskra, Algeria; Oases
- Two men picking oranges in Biskra (one of which is Taylor's guide) (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref27; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Oases; Food; Agriculture/Farms; Biskra, Algeria; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Palm Trees; El Kantara, Algeria; Deserts; Camels; Animals; Railways; Streets/Roads
- Mr. Shepherd riding a camel held by their guide, alongside three other men and a boy riding a camel (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref28; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Men; Smoking; Group Portraits; Hats; Camels; Animals; Palm Trees; Streets/Roads; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Fez/Tarboush; Girls; Biskra, Algeria
- A view of the 'modern' section of Biskra taken from the Royal Hotel., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref29; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hotels; Biskra, Algeria; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Oases; Deserts; Camels; Food; Statues/Sculptures
- A portrait of a man with four camels in the Sahara Desert., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref30; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Men; Camels; Animals; Individual Portraits; Deserts; Dancing; Musical Instruments; Music; Biskra, Algeria
- A portrait of Mr. Shepherd with a boy, the boy rides his bicycle., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref31; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Music; Bicycles/Tricycles; Boys; Children; Men; Smoking; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Deserts; Camels; Animals; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Regional/National Dress
- A view of the village of Sidi Okba in the Sahara Desert, an oasis lines the horizon (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref32; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Deserts; Oases; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Landscapes
- People at the market in Sidi Okba (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref33; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Buildings; Architecture; Markets; Crowds; Tents; Regional/National Dress; Children; Boys; Men; Girls; Hats; Head Covers/Veils; Palm Trees; Deserts; Biskra, Algeria; El Kantara, Algeria; Hotels; Donkeys; Animals; Deserts; Oases
- A view of Chabet-el-Akra., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref34; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Water; Rivers; Mountains/Hills; Chabet el Akra, Taskriout, Algeria; Food; Kherrata, Algeria
- A view of Chabet-el-Akra (Ravine of Death)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref35; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Chabet el Akra, Taskriout, Algeria; Kherrata, Algeria
- A view of Chabet-el-Akra (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref36; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Chabet el Akra, Taskriout, Algeria; Kherrata, Algeria; Mountains/Hills; Children; Rivers; Water; Bridges
- A view of Chabet-el-Akra (Ravine of Death), Kherata., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref37; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Chabet el Akra, Taskriout, Algeria; Kherrata, Algeria; Water; Rivers; Streets/Roads
- A view of the Thimble Rock in Chabet-el-Akra., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref38; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Kherrata, Algeria; Chabet el Akra, Taskriout, Algeria; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Streets/Roads; Men; Monuments/Memorials; Cameras; Civil Engineering
- A view of the Death Pass in Kherata., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref39; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Seas; Water; Mountains/Hills; Kherrata, Algeria; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Streets/Roads
- A portrait of a group hiking in the Djurdjura Mountains, Kabylia., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref40; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Countryside/Rural; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Algeria
- A view of fig trees in the Djurdjura Mountains, Kabylia (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref41; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Countryside/Rural; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Algeria
- A view of Merchalla, a village in the Djurdjura Mountains., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref42; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Men; Food; Countryside/Rural
- A group portrait of several men and children with H.E. Irving Taylor and Shepherd in Merchalla., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref43; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Men; Group Portraits; Hats; Canes/Walking Sticks; Boys; Children; Girls; Facial Hair; Algiers, Algeria; Countryside/Rural
- A eucalyptus forest near Algiers., Dec 1901; AD_MC_040_ref44; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Forest/Woodlands; Algiers, Algeria; Countryside/Rural
- A portrait of a man standing on an 'Avenue of Bananas' near Algiers., Dec 1901; AD_MC_040_ref45; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Forest/Woodlands; Algiers, Algeria; Countryside/Rural; Men; Hats; Individual Portraits
- A walkway lined with bamboo trees near Algiers., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref46; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Forest/Woodlands; Countryside/Rural; Streets/Roads; Algiers, Algeria
- A walkway lined with India-rubber trees near Algiers., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref47; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Forest/Woodlands; Countryside/Rural; Algiers, Algeria
- A walkway lined with 'Ivy-covered Plane-trees' near Algiers., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref48; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Forest/Woodlands; Streets/Roads; Algiers, Algeria; Parks; Gardens
- A walkway lined with plane trees near Algiers., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref49; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Forest/Woodlands; Streets/Roads; Gardens; Parks; Algiers, Algeria
- A portrait of three people standing at the entrance to a date palm avenue near Algiers., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref50; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Forest/Woodlands; Group Portraits; Women; Men; Hats; Palm Trees
- A view of palm trees and banana plants in the Botanical Garden Hamma (Jardin d'Essai) in Belouizdad, Algiers., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref51; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Forest/Woodlands; Palm Trees; Gardens; Parks; Algiers, Algeria
- Bottle palm trees in the Botanical Garden Hamma (Jardin d'Essai) in Belouizdad, Algiers., Jan 1902; AD_MC_040_ref52; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Palm Trees; Forest/Woodlands; Gardens; Parks; Algiers, Algeria
- A view of the governor's palace (Palais du Peuple) at 'Mustapha Superieur' in Algiers., Apr 1902; AD_MC_040_ref53; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Sidi M'Hamed, Algiers, Algeria; Buildings; Women; Hats; Streets/Roads; Statues/Sculptures; Boys; Children; Regional/National Dress; Umbrellas/Parasols; Flags; Architecture; Palaces; Palm Trees
- A portrait of a woman standing amongst Algerian fennel., Apr 1902; AD_MC_040_ref54; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; English Writing; Women; Countryside/Rural; Algeria; Hats
- A blank page in the album 'A Trip in Algeria'., Circa December 1901 – April 1902; AD_MC_040_ref55; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)
- A blank page in the album 'A Trip in Algeria'., Circa December 1901 – April 1902; AD_MC_040_ref56; Taylor, H.E. Irving; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_040)